enca.com 2019-05-04

# Privacy Policy | eNCA

eNews Channel Africa (eNCA) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our Privacy Policy and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is utilised by us. Certain pages on our website have been structured so that you can access the site without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. However, should you wish to make full use of the eNCA site, you may be required to register and provide us with personal information. We have therefore made this notice available on our home page and at the bottom of every page that collects personal information.

eNCA has developed its privacy practices in line with the South African draft bill on the Protection of Personal Information, the Canadian Standards Association’s Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information as well as the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor principles. A complete copy of the Model Code is available at <http://www.csa.ca/standards/privacy/>. More information about the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

### **APPLICABILITY**

This Privacy Policy applies to the eNCA website, which includes the eNCA mobile websites, only. This statement is not applicable to other related websites not specifically included.

The eNCA website may contain links to or from other sites ("linked sites"), including sites maintained by eNCA but which are not governed by this Privacy Policy. Accordingly, eNCA is in no way responsible for the content or the privacy and security policies employed by linked sites.

Certain services are linked with those linked sites, some which offer you the option to share with both eNCA and the third party personal data that you provide or content that you post on the eNCA website. However, eNCA will not share your personal information with those linked sites unless you make that choice. 

### **TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**

When you register on the eNCA website for any reason, such as to receive email newsletters or to post content to the site, we collect certain information about you in order to provide you with the services you have requested. This information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Name;
  * Email address;
  * Physical or postal address
  * Contact telephone numbers
  * Information you choose to share from third party websites, such as social media websites;

Once you choose to register with eNCA and provide us with personal information, it will be used for the purposes of providing you with the requested service and in conformity with the provisions of the Electronic Communications and Transactions Act 25/2002. We respect your privacy and undertake not to sell, rent or lease your personal information to others.

Certain non-personal information may be collected while you are using the website. This will comprise of data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity. eNCA may collect and use this non-personal information to evaluate how the eNCA website is being used. 

Most non-personal data may be collected via cookies or other analysis technologies. The eNCA website pages normally use cookies for data analysis and potential personalization of the website and services offered.

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide features that recognize your account as logged on and other website features. Further, to help us tailor the website to the needs and interests of our users, or for other purposes, we may gather aggregate, permanently non-personally identifiable information via cookies. Examples include the type of Internet browser our users are using, the frequency of visits to our site and which pages our users viewed. We may share these aggregate statistics with others. The use of cookies is standard on the Internet and many major web sites use them.

Technologies may vary, but in many cases may involve a small file stored locally on the computer used to access the eNCA website, and may be used to store and collect information relating to your viewing and use of the eNCA website. Information collected through cookies is used to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information we keep on individual users that details their preferences, their use and request history and behavioral activity, and can minimise the need for you to re-enter information.

When you access the eNCA website as an unregistered user, we use cookies to identify your browser when you use the website. However, the information collected is anonymous, meaning only your browser rather than you as a user can be identified using this information. We use cookies so that we can provide a better service to you (for example, so that we can recommend content based on which stories you have read).

Most cookies expire after a defined period of time, or you can delete your cookie file at any time. Most web browser software is initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your web browser software to refuse cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some parts of our website will not function properly or may be considerably slower if you refuse cookies. For example, without cookies, you will not be able to set personalised preferences.

In order to better enable advertisers to assess the suitability of the website for advertising and to target their advertising to specific sections or kinds of pages, eNCA.com uses tags provided by Effective Measure, as mandated by the Digital Media and Marketing Association, to collect anonymous information regarding site usage. You can read the Effective Measure privacy policy at[ ](http://http//www.effectivemeasure.com/privacy-policy)<http://www.effectivemeasure.com/privacy-policy>. We also use tags from DoubleClick [http://www.google.com/doubleclick](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/) and use anonymous information collected from these tags to allow advertisers to serve advertising content on the website.

eNCA may collect your computer’s IP (Internet Protocol) address and domain name address, the identity of your Internet service or access provider, the type of web browsing software you use, your computers operating system, the URL of the web page from which you came to visit our website and the language you selected for your web browsing software (collectively referred to herein as clickstream data). We use these technologies to identify our users, to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the eNCA website and the services offered thereon.

eNCA needs and uses your personal information to provide you with the services you request and to help us better understand your needs and interests in the future. Specifically, eNCA uses your information to help you complete and provide the services you have requested. Sensitive personal information if collected will only be used if you choose to allow us to do this in terms of your personal preferences options and will be shared only with your express permission.

Personal data given to eNCA may be transferred across state and country borders for the purposes of data consolidation, storage and simplified customer information management. 

### **HOW ENCA WILL SHARE YOUR INFORMATION AND WITH WHOM?**

eNCA will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information.

eNCA may partner with other organizations who may provide you with the services requested through the eNCA website. These partner organisation are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of eNCA and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for eNCA. eNCA will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law enforcement action, subpoena, or local law. 

### **PRIVACY PREFERENCES**

eNCA will not use your personal information for a different purpose than the one stated when you provided your data. Examples of unrelated uses include sending communications about updated information, new services and marketing messages. You can, however, choose to receive these types of non-subscription communications by ticking the box when you register.

### **DATA ACCESS, ACCURACY, AMENDMENTS, RETENTION AND OPTING OUT**

eNCA will try to keep your personal information accurate. We will provide you with access to your information, including making reasonable efforts to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change your information, if possible. To protect your privacy and security, when doing so we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data.

Upon request, eNCA will:

  * Correct personal information that you state is incorrect; or
  * Permit you to “opt out” of further contact (excepting notification of major changes to the service), either on the original site of registration or at any time subsequently, while still allowing basic access to the site;
  * Remove you and your personal information provided electronically from our database, thereby cancelling your registration.

To request a correction or cancellation, send an e-mail to the address provided to you at registration for this purpose.

### **SECURITY**

eNCA undertakes to take all reasonable measures to protect the information you provide us. These measures include, but are not limited to preventing unauthorised access or disclosure, maintaining data accuracy, and ensuring the appropriate use of the information. eNCA has in place reasonable physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. 

### **CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT**

Please note that these guidelines are subject to change at any time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. You are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy at the inception of each session.

### **LAW AND JURISDICTION**

This Privacy Policy is governed by the Laws of the Republic of South Africa and without regard to the conflict of laws principle. You agree that any cause of action that may arise under this Privacy Policy shall be commenced and be heard in the appropriate court in South Africa. You agree to submit to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within South Africa.

### **ACCEPTANCE OF POLICY**

By using this website, or otherwise providing your personal information to eNCA, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the eNCA website or provide any personal information to eNCA.

**Effective date of policy: 31 March 2013**
